(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T02:17:50.593349",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あ、こっちこっちこっち！
Ah, over here, over here, over here!
今日お二人じゃないんすね
You're not together today, huh?
え？お二人？
Huh? Together?
さっきの...
From earlier...
ここで会った人たち
The people he met here.
え？
Huh?
ここ...
Here...
パレードへ
...to the parade...
JOYにこうぜ！
Let's go with JOY!
JOYSOUND X1
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
ATTENTION ご来場のお客様へ
ATTENTION: To All Attendees
天音かなた 1st Solo Live LOCK ON!
[Title: Amane Kanata 1st Solo Live LOCK ON!]
Three, two, one
Amane Kanata 1st Solo Live 「LOCK ON」
[Amane Kanata 1st Solo Live: LOCK ON]
あ、あ、あ
Ah, ah, ah...
聞こえますか、皆さん？
Can you hear me, everyone?
イェーイ！本日は天音かなた 1st Solo Live「LOCK ON」にご来場いただき、ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much for coming to Amane Kanata 1st Solo Live "LOCK ON" today!
天音かなたでーす！イェーイ！
I'm Amane Kanata! Yay!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
To make sure you enjoy the show until the very end, I have a few announcements.
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
Photography, audio recording, and the use of recording equipment during the show are strictly prohibited.
そして、みんな、万が一具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、絶対に無理をせず、お近くのスタッフへお知らせください。絶対にね！
And if anyone feels unwell, please don't push yourselves and let a nearby staff member know. Promise me, okay?
絶対だよ！おーい！
Promise, okay? Hey!
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ステージに物を投げ込むなど、他のみんなの迷惑になったり公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。ルールを守って盛り上がってください！
Moshing, diving, throwing objects onto the stage, or any behavior that disturbs others or interferes with the show is strictly prohibited. Please follow the rules and enjoy!
偉い！
Good job!
本公演は映像配信、写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合がございます！
Please note that live stream and photo cameras are inside the venue, and audience seats may be captured on camera!
イェーイ、いいよな！映像や写真はプロモーションなどに使用される可能性がございますので、あらかじめご了承ください！
Yay, that's fine, right? The footage and photos may be used for promotional purposes, so please be aware in advance!
はーい、ありがとう！
Alright, thank you!
また、ライブのハッシュタグは #打ち抜けかなた なので、みんなハッシュタグを使って、配信で見てくれてるみんなも...
Also, the concert hashtag is #打ち抜けかなた, so please use the hashtag, and for everyone watching the stream too...
お前らは、あの、帰り道かな？帰り道にね、あの、またハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてください！
As for those here, maybe on your way home? On your way home, please use the hashtag and post lots of hype!
ありがとう！それでは開演までもう少し、みんなで一緒に盛り上がっていきましょう！
Thank you! Now then, there's just a little time left until start time, so let's all get hyped up together!
どどん！前進上等！ちゃんと歓迎して
Boom! Advance forward! Welcome me properly!
(wonder-la-der-la) 高まれ
(wonder-la-der-la) Get hyped up!
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して
Creating sea and sky, marvel at it properly!
(wonder-la-der-la) 興奮しよう
(wonder-la-der-la) Let me see your excitement!
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Because I say so! Because I'm really gonna do it!
現実超えろ未来 あー！
Surpass reality into the future, ah!
弱点も平気スイッチでランチャー！
Weak points are fine, hit the switch and launch!
(wonder-la-der-la)
すなわち特者生存ワンダーランダday
In short, survival of the special, wonder-landa day!
(wonder-la-der-la) 楽しもう
(wonder-la-der-la) Let's have fun!
面白がれること探したまえ over? 返事聞かせてくれ！
Go search for fun things to enjoy, over? Let me hear your answer!
右左なんかじゃない (かなたーん！)
It's not about left or right! (Kanatan!)
決めつけて一直線 (かなたーん！)
Set your sight straight ahead! (Kanatan!)
つまり企んだら発射オーライだ
In short, once planned, all systems go!
ワクワクするぜ！しゃー！
I'm so pumped up! Yeah!
Amane Kanata 1st Solo Live LOOK ON
knock it out！
Knock it out!
熱情
Passion!
先駆け撃ち
Pioneering strike,
最強
The strongest!
望まれて
Desired,
愛され系
The beloved type,
get you now！
Get you now!
光を魅せて oh
Show me your light, oh
1回 2回
Once, twice...
見せかけはしないで
Don't just make it a show.
止めないで高鳴り
Don't stop this pounding pulse,
鏡にはつぎはぎ
patched together in the mirror.
唯一の心 揺らして
Shake your one and only heart.
あっちの非難のケア ノックアウト
Dealing with criticism over there, knock out!
声高くハイハイハイ
Raise your voice high, hey, hey, hey!
無敵のアイアイアイアイ愛だ
It's invincible love, love, love, love, love!
惹きつけろ ほらディスコグラフィ
Captivate them, look, discography!
脳内ナイナイ秘められぬ
In my brain, no, no, I can't hide it,
野心初速燃やせライ
burn your initial ambition speed, light!
行くぞー！ ありあがりー！
Let's go! Thank you so much!
ずっと正解と待ち構えてた
I've been waiting for the correct answer all along,
眩しさは狂い始めるバンとリロード
the dazzling light begins to go crazy, bang and reload!
警告！ 逃走へ！
Warning! To escape!
危機あきたよ 遠吠えなの？
Tired of crises, is that a howl?
夢見てても起きてなきゃ意味がない
Even if you dream, it's meaningless unless you're awake.
傷ついても勝たせて
Even if I get hurt, let me win.
体中 音響かせて
Make the sound resonate through my body.
躍らせて強がりに
Let me dance to my bluffing,
欲張りで華麗にセーイ
greedily and splendidly say!
切り抜けて 嘘で化けた
Break through, disguised in lies,
だんだんだんだん
gradually, gradually...
今夜は君なんだ
Tonight, it's you,
笑顔で入れちゃうおまじない
a spell put in with a smile.
本気？嘘？
Serious? A lie?
君の隣に居たいな
I want to be by your side.
無敵のアイアイアイアイ愛だ
It's invincible love, love, love, love, love!
惹きつけろ ほらディスコグラフィ
Captivate them, look, discography!
脳内ナイナイ秘められぬ
In my brain, no, no, I can't hide it,
野心初速 壊せライ
break your initial ambition speed, light!
クラップしてください！
Please clap your hands!
きっと一人ぼっちの私
Surely, being all alone,
シャッター街に居たって
even standing in a deserted shopping street,
不安 不安 不安ばっか
nothing but anxiety, anxiety, anxiety,
また追い込んじゃったんだ
I've driven myself into a corner again.
ちかちか真っ赤な電灯
A flickering crimson light,
消し去った誰か
someone erased it.
グラグラ運んでいた
I was carrying it unsteadily,
いなくなっちゃった
and now it's gone.
カンカンって踏切から
Clanging from the railroad crossing,
赤信号が長くて
the red light stays on for long,
からからにして
leaving me completely dried up,
またつっかかっちゃってんだ
getting stuck once again.
フラフラって搬送されちゃって
Staggering and being carried away,
ナイナイサー
no, no, sir!
あれ？あれ？聞こえますか？
Huh? Huh? Can you hear me?
これ泣くなっちゃいますか？
Will I end up crying from this?
欠陥品の頂上目指して
Aiming for the top as a defective product,
ノックダウンして見下して
knocking down and looking down on others,
あの欠点だらけの
how was that full-of-flaws,
壊滅な自分はどうでした？
ruined self of mine?
あわよくばこう見て
If possible, look at it like this,
ただ置き去りになれ
just get left behind,
この好都合な良い子になるまで
until I become a convenient good girl.
愛してあげるね
I'll love you, okay?
大丈夫
It's fine.
どんな薬品に浸して
Soaking in whatever chemicals,
身体中に毒を燃やして
burning poison throughout the body,
骨の髄まで ちゃんと奥まで
down to the marrow, deep inside,
愛！愛！愛！ライ！
Love! Love! Love! Lie!
泣きたいよ 寂しいよ
I want to cry, I'm lonely,
一人ぼっちのままに
remaining all alone,
惨めになっちゃって
becoming miserable.
愛しいね
How lovely,
可愛いね
how cute,
お目目に映った
reflected in my eyes,
ブタの頭のぬいぐるみ
a pig-headed stuffed toy.
慰めてた言葉も探さず
Without even searching for comforting words,
撫で撫でしてあげるから
I'll pat your head,
お上手にあいよが上手だね
you're so good at giving affection.
えっへん！えっへん！やったね！
Ahem! Ahem! Yay!
生気が失せたね
Your energy has drained,
息が切れたね
you're out of breath,
一人だけで今日も過ごせたね
you spent today all alone again.
耳が上手ね
You're good at listening,
口が上手ね
you're good with words,
泣いてたって気にかけちゃうって
even when crying, you still care,
君の事だから
because that's how you are.
忘れてすべてを
Forget everything,
巻き戻して私
rewind me,
あり得ない声を
an unbelievable voice,
愛おしくて愛おしくてたまらない
I love it so much I can't stand it.
でも多分一発じゃ伝わらないから
But it probably won't reach in one shot,
取っておきあげようか
so shall I give you my special prize?
いくらダメダメ言われても
No matter how much they say no,
言いたいことが言えるのね
you can say what you want to say.
あーあ
Ah...
しゃーないね
It can't be helped.
君のせいじゃないもんね
It's not your fault, after all.
しゃーないね しゃーないね
It can't be helped, it can't be helped.
あーあ あーあ
Ah, ah...
もうそんな傷つけたりしないで
Don't hurt yourself like that anymore.
大丈夫 安全だよね
It's okay, we're safe, right?
新しい世界に来れば
If you come to this new world...
見捨てないから ずっと今日も
I won't abandon you, today and forever...
一生 UNLOCK UNLOCK
Forever UNLOCK UNLOCK!
頼っていた 案外気楽になれる
Relying on it, you can become surprisingly at ease.
普遍的な天命になるまで愛してあげるね
I'll love you until it becomes a universal destiny.
大丈夫 どんどん良くなって
It's okay, it's getting better and better.
美しさに声を焦がして
Burning my voice for beauty.
隠せるチャクラい 笑っちゃうくらい
Chakra enough to hide it, enough to laugh about it,
ちゃんと愛 愛 愛 Love You!
properly love, love, love... Love You!
自分、陰キャですから...
After all... I'm an introvert...
あー怖い！
Ah, scary!
人間が怖い！
Humans are scary!
見ないで！見ないで！
Don't look! Don't look!
でもちょっとは見てもろて...
But please look at me just a little...
おどおど おどおど もごもご もごもご
Timid, timid, mumbling, mumbling...
悲しき陰キャのララバイ
The sad lullaby of an introvert.
あんの？ あんの？ インドア派？
Anyone? Anyone? Indoor type?
今日も今日とて自己嫌悪
Self-loathing again today.
あんの？ あんの？ インドア派？
Anyone? Anyone? Indoor type?
世界で一番全否定！
Total rejection, most in the world!
袖が余ったら漏れる泣き声
If the sleeves are too long, weeping leaks out.
え？あ、ふんふん...え？あ、いいな...うん、うん...
(Eh? Ah, mm-hmm... Eh? Ah, nice... Yeah, yeah...)
お呼びでないのかな？ 湯に浸かる
Am I not welcome? Soaking in the bath...
脳内会議始動！
Brainstorming meeting activated!
うるせぇ！
Shut up!
知らねぇ！
I don't care!
見るな！
Don't look!
逆ギレ気持ちいいな！
Misplaced anger feels so good!
挙動不審でごめんなさい
Sorry for acting suspicious.
ただ嫌われたくないだけなので
It's just that I don't want to be hated.
震える声で語るわ
I'll speak with a trembling voice.
汗ドバドバドバ！
Sweat pouring down!
笑おう 笑おう せめて笑おう
Let me smile, let me smile, at least let me smile...
なるほどです！
I see!
後悔 後悔 から回り
Regret, regret, running in circles!
反省 反省 また反省だ
Reflecting, reflecting, reflecting again!
胸の中ではバンバン強い奴なのに
Even though I'm super strong inside my heart...
明日は今日より人間になりたい！
Tomorrow, I want to be human more than today!
おうち帰りたい！
I want to go home!
インドア派！
Indoor type!
真っ暗お部屋でひきこもりたい！
I want to shut myself in a pitch-black room!
あんの？ あんの？ インドア派？
Anyone? Anyone? Indoor type?
空回り行動で後悔中
Regretting my futile actions.
空気を読むこと育成中
Currently learning how to read the room...
声なき声に耳をすまし
Listening closely to the voiceless voices.
ブれず 媚びず 関わらず
Unshaken, unswayed, uninvolved...
そう 誰が呼んだか 陰の者
Yes, who called me the creature of the shadows?
陰キャと呼ばれるこの生物は、頭の中で妄想や反省会を繰り広げており...
This creature known as an introvert is constantly running delusions and reflection sessions in their head...
「待って！褒めないで！近寄らないで！」なんて言いながら...
while saying things like, "Wait! Don't praise me! Don't come near me!"...
妄想の先輩と妄想の同人誌を展開し...
and expanding delusional fan fiction with delusional seniors...
そして無事にショートして思考停止するのである！
ultimately short-circuiting and freezing their brain entirely!
うわぁぁぁ！
Uwaaaah!
急に話しかけちゃ嫌！
Don't suddenly talk to me, no!
やだやだやだやだ！
No no no no!
雑談トークの特訓中！
Currently training in small talk!
やだやだやだ！
No no no!
誰かが乗ってるエレベーター！
An elevator with someone already inside!
そう 我らこそ 陰の者
Yes, we are the creatures of the shadows.
陰キャに愛を！ 陰キャに愛を！ 陰キャに愛を！
Love for introverts! Love for introverts! Love for introverts!
悲しき陰キャのララバイ
The sad lullaby of an introvert.
目と目が合わずにごめんなさい
Sorry for not making eye contact.
明るい人には眩しくて
Cheerful people are too bright for me.
話が続かずごめんなさい
Sorry for not being able to keep the conversation going.
この会話もすべて手紙形式で！
Even this conversation is all written like a letter!
挙動不審でごめんなさい
Sorry for acting suspicious.
ただ嫌われたくないだけなので
It's just that I don't want to be hated.
貼り付く笑顔 汗ドバドバドバ！
Plastered smile, sweat pouring down!
笑おう 笑おう せめて笑おう
Let me smile, let me smile, at least let me smile...
なるほどです！
I see!
後悔 後悔 から回り
Regret, regret, running in circles!
反省 反省 また反省だ
Reflecting, reflecting, reflecting again!
鏡ですら目を見らせないか
Can't even look myself in the eye in the mirror?
明日は今日より人間になりたい！
Tomorrow, I want to be human more than today!
帰りたい！ 帰りたい！
I want to go home! I want to go home!
おうち！
Home!
今日も今日とてごめんなさい！
Sorry again today!
あんの？ あんの？ インドア派？
Anyone? Anyone? Indoor type?
どうしてこんなに泣きたいの？
Why do I want to cry like this?
インドア派！
Indoor type!
真っ暗お部屋で引きこもり！
Shutting myself in a pitch-black room!
あんの？ あんの？ インドア派？
Anyone? Anyone? Indoor type?
意味なくうなずく ありえない！
Nodding for no reason? Unbelievable!
みんなー！
Everyone~!
ちょっと水飲んで...水飲みますね、一回。
Let me drink some water... I'll take a quick water break.
おーい！
Hey~!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
はい、ということでですね、へいコンカナタ！
Alright then! Heykonkanata!
最高！
Awesome!
はい、キャッチコピーは握力50キロ、ギュッギュッ握りつぶしちゃうぞ。ホロライブ4期生、かなたんこと天音かなたでーす！
My catchphrase is "50kg grip strength, I'll crush you tight!" Hololive 4th gen's Kanatan, a.k.a. Amane Kanata!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
ということでみんな、天音かなた 1st Solo Live "LOCK ON!" にお越しくださりありがとうございます！
So everyone, thank you so much for coming to Amane Kanata 1st Solo Live "LOCK ON!"!
いや、本当にね、初めてのソロライブですよ。
Really, this is my very first solo live concert.
ちょっと皆さん、僕も念願でしたが、ちょっとヘイ民のみんなもこの日を楽しみにして待ってたんじゃないのー？
Everyone, this was my long-cherished dream, but weren't all you Heymin waiting for this day with excitement too?!
ありがとうございます！いや本当にね、僕の今までの活動をちょっとここにね、気持ちとかも全部みんなと一緒にぶつけていけたらいいなと思ってるので、今日1日楽しんでください！
Thank you so much! I want to channel all my feelings from my journey so far together with you, so please enjoy today to the fullest!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
はい、みたいな感じでね、あの、みんなアルバムいっぱい聴いてくれた？コールマジで凄いじゃん！笑うー！
Alright! Did everyone listen to the album a lot? Your chants are seriously amazing! I can't help but laugh!
凄い！覚えてきてくれたんだね、ギリギリだったのにありがとう！
Amazing! You memorized them for me! Even though time was so tight, thank you!
ありがとうね！めっちゃギリギリだったのにありがとう！
Thank you! Even though it was super short notice, thank you!
え、そして皆さん、ちょっと紹介したいものがありまして！なんと！今回ガールズバンド引き連れてきましたー！
Ah, and everyone, there's something I'd like to introduce! Believe it or not, I brought a girls band along with me!
凄い！いやもうね、僕夢でしたね。ガールズバンドというものが。
Amazing! Man, having a girls band has really been a dream of mine!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you so much!
本当に可愛いくて！可愛いんですよ、皆さん！
They're really so cute! They are so cute, everyone!
あの、腕章も、生徒会の腕章もね、もう忘れ去られた初期の設定ですね！
Look at their armbands, the Student Council armbands! That initial lore setting that was almost forgotten!
こちらもね、つけてくれてるから、僕あの生徒会のね、初期なんだけど覚えてるー？
They're wearing them for me! I was originally in the Student Council, do you remember that?!
あ、覚えてるわ！初期だから生徒会長じゃないからね、はい！
Ah, you do remember! Since it was the beginning, I wasn't the Student Council President yet though!
ありがとう！ありがとうね！
Thank you! Thank you!
という感じでですね、憧れ、夢だったソロライブとガールズバンド、そしてみんなが...ありがとう！
And so, my dream solo live, a girls band, and all of you... Thank you!
配信でもね、配信の配信のオンラインも見れてたらなー！
To everyone watching the stream online as well...
ありがとう！こう推しカメラっていうのがありまして、ちょっと配信上ではね、イエーイ！アピールしてるんで！
Thank you! We have an "Oshi Camera", so on the stream, I'm posing like "Yay!"
まぁね、現地にいるみんなも配信では見てくれてるだろうから、可愛いくアピっとくわね！可愛ーい？ありがとー！
Well, everyone here in person will probably rewatch the stream later, so I'll pose cute for you! Am I cute? Thank you!
すご！これ脳汁がドバドバ出ますね！
Awesome! This is really getting the brain juices flowing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ライブのね、感想もコメントも「イエーイ！うぉー！見てる！」って言ってる。見てる見てる、見てるよー！ありがとう！
I see your comments and thoughts about the live... "Yay! Whoa! I'm watching!" I see you, I see you! Thank you!
ということで、こうやってね、ライブの感想なんですが、ハッシュタグ #打ち抜けかなた で、配信で見てるお前らも、現地のみんなは帰り際とか帰ったらとかになんだけど、#打ち抜けかなた でたくさんポストしてください！
So please post your thoughts on the live using the hashtag #打ち抜けかなた ! Whether you're on stream or here at the venue, post a lot with #打ち抜けかなた !
ありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you so much!
そして何とですね、ちょっと悲しいお知らせがここで...
And now, I have a slightly sad announcement to make here...
YouTube、TikTokで無料チラ見せを見ている方は...ごめん！ここまでです！
For those watching the free preview on YouTube and TikTok... Sorry! This is where it ends!
な、そんなー！何だってー！
Wha— No way?! Say what?!
えーということでね、すみません、ここからあの、有料になってしまいます。有料コンテンツですね。あんなすごいことが起きるかもしれませんよ！
So yeah, I'm sorry, but from here on out it becomes paid content. Who knows, something incredible might happen!
やばーい！ということで、まだまだ一緒に盛り上がりたい方は、概要欄から配信サイトへよろしくお願いいたします！何が起こるか分からなーい！
Oh no! If you want to keep hyping up together, please check out the streaming site link in the description! Anything could happen!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
そしてですね、ステージの変化、みんな気づいた？気づきましたか？
And also, did everyone notice the change on stage? Did you notice?
凄いでしょ！さっきまで羽が開いてたんですけど、ご覧の通り閉じました！
Isn't it amazing?! The wings were open until just now, but as you can see, they closed!
これ、ま、じゃあやっぱセオリーで考えますと、みんなの声が足りないってやつじゃないのー？！
Now, thinking about this logically based on concert rules... doesn't this mean your cheering isn't loud enough?!
もっともっと！もっともっと！おーい！
More, more! More, more! Hey!
きたー！やるやん！やるやん、みんなー！ありがとう！
There it is! Way to go! Way to go, everyone! Thank you!
みんなのおかげで羽も...
Thanks to everyone, the wings...
ね
You know...
開きましたよ
They've opened up!
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
みんなの... あ！
Everyone's... Ah!
ほら 静かになれば「かなた可愛い」...
See, if it gets quiet, someone will say "Kanata's cute..."
可愛い 可愛い 可愛い ありがとうございます
Cute, cute, cute... Thank you very much!
ということでね
And with that...
羽も... ありがとう！
The wings too... Thank you!
開きました！みんなの声も出てきたので
...have opened! Now that everyone's warmed up...
次の曲、行ってみよう！
Let's move on to the next song!
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free preview has ended. Thank you for watching!